

# JADE JOHNSON

Freelance Lead UX Designer based in Berlin

www.linkedin.com/in/jadejohnsonux www.sistercircuitlab.com

Passionate about humanising products to make people's lives easier. Specialising in strategy, systems optimisation, product-market fit and edge-cases, I'm collaboratively impacting global clients like NASA and Delivery Hero. My deductive reasoning processes combine business goals, customer insights, scientific data and testing methods to validate design decisions and develop sustainable customer solutions.

# SKILLS

Project Management	InVision, Prototyping	
User Experience Design	Product Roadmaps	
Product Design Strategy	AB, Usability Testing	
JIRA, Sprints, Backlog	Wordpress, Workshops	
User Research	KPI's, OKR's	
Data Analysis, GAnalytics	Adobe Creative Suite	
Sketch, Figma, Wireframe	Agile, SCRUM	

# **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

General Assembly Certificate, User Experience Design Immersive	02/2016	
CSU Los Angeles BA (honors), Fashion Design and Textiles  • Creative Director of Fashion Association with focus on Electronic Music Production.	06/2011	
Lynda.com Certificate, Agile Foundations and Cross-Cultural Awareness	11/2019	
SinnerSchrader ngGirls Certificate, AngularJS, CSS, HTML	05/2018	
Atomic Design Systems Conference		
Smashing Conference Global UX and Web Design	04/2018	
Google UX Workshop Mobile Web Page Speed Improvement	02/2018	
Facebook Platform Meetup Startups, Chatsbots, Engagement, GDPR	12/2017	
Google Director Luke Wroblewski Obvious Always Wins: UX Mobile Web	09/2017	
World Information Architecture Day		
Jared Spool UIE Data Metrics: Is Design Metrically Opposed?	01/2016	

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Sistercircuitlab.com Freelance Lead Designer and Consultant

01/2010 - Present

### CareerFoundry Freelance UX Design Mentor

07/2020 - Present

• Preparing Students to become successful UX Design professionals with portfolio development video advising and Mentorship calls.

# Delivery Hero Lead UX/UI and Product Designer

09/2017 - 09/2019

- · Released largest brand's new design, doubling CVR via CRO.
- Created roadmaps from OKR's and KPI's, built JIRA sprintboard and product backlog.
- Validated hypothesis: wrote user stories, wireframes, mockups, AB and Usability Testing.
- Built design community, hired, trained, hosted Stakeholder UX ROI workshops.
- Developed InVision Design System and Mobile Web UXBP Playbook with Google.

### Blackrock Web Solutions Lead UX/UI Designer

01/2017 - 05/2017

- Led MedTech Team in developing custom enterprise SaaS for Government Embassy.
- Analysed, planned, facilitated design of CRM and EHR for medical web software platform.
- Conducted user interviews and ethnographic research with Health Ministry employees.
- Developed personas, automated workflow processes into digital storyboards and userflows.

#### **Lunawork** Freelance Senior UX/UI Designer and Consultant

07/2016 - 12/2016

• Designed interface and userflows for stealth employment iOS/Android App.

#### NASA Freelance UX Designer and System Architect

01/2016 - 03/2016

- Developed system architecture schemas for ISS Astronauts' Asst, Astrobee's, robotic arm.
- Managed project by analysing business needs, planning and consulting on which roles to fill.

### HopSkipDrive Freelance UX Designer and Information Architect

01/2016 - 02/2016

- Created userflows and features for parents to start carpool groups and book rides via iOS App.
- Guided User Interviews and developed market personas based on data insights and research.

#### OTIS College of Art and Design Product Design Instructor

09/2011 - 07/2012

Facilitated career success of 90 Students in 3 Product Development courses.